Name: Peter Jacobs

Email: thisispeterj@gmail.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/thisispeterj/

Github: github.com/thisispeterj Contact Number: (408) 610-0117

Summary:

QA Engineer with 10 years of experience in manual testing and a strong understanding of the software development life cycle. Adept at creating and executing test cases and identifying and reporting defects using various tools. Committed to collaborating with both developers and business teams to resolve defects and improve software functionality and usability.

Skills:

- Test Case Design and Execution
- Manual and Automation Testing
- Defect Tracking and Reporting
- Agile Development

Tools and Software:

- HTML, CSS, Javascript, Nightwatch.js, SQL, Git, Unix
- Jira, GitHub, Jenkins, iTerm, Postico, Postman, SoapUI, Chrome Developer Tools, Slack, Asana

Work Experience:

Senior QA Engineer at EKA Solutions Inc. (2017-2022)

- Worked as the lead tester for a React.js SAAS transportation management system (TMS)
- Conducted manual and automated testing for all stages of development and deployment: Local, Development instance, Staging instance, and finally smoke testing in production
- Attended weekly business meetings to assess upcoming stories and priorities
- Attended sprint planning to review all stories for upcoming sprint, using tools such as Jira to track all of our stories.
- Attended and led QA meetings to write test cases and discuss the priorities for the upcoming sprint
- Tested APIs from various integrations using tools SoapUI and Postman
- Used postico and SQL to manipulate the postgreSQL database
- Tracked and reported issues using Jira and assigned priority

- Maintained documentation for new and existing features
- Used Jenkins to monitor our pipeline

Client Support and QA Engineer at ImageShack (2013-2016)

- Conducted manual and automated testing for all stages of development and deployment: Local, Development instance, Staging instance, and finally smoke testing in production
- Tracked and reported issues using Jira
- Provided both phone and email support for customers
- Created a custom Zendesk help and support center
- Worked with CEO on increasing subscriptions, retention, and customer satisfaction

Education:

High School Diploma, Gilroy High School, (2000 - 2003)
Bachelor of Science in Computer Video Imaging, Cogswell Polytechnical College, (2003-2005)